<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on WY Computer Science</title>
    <link>http://wy-cs.info/resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on WY Computer Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 15:49:20 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://wy-cs.info/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus: All Courses</title>
      <link>http://wy-cs.info/resources/generic-cs-syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 15:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wy-cs.info/resources/generic-cs-syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Computer Science Syllabus Overview The most important information (contact information, grading scale) comes first. Anything you need that you do not see here, check the following sources:
 Class web site resources section Email me and ask: amauer-oats@cps.edu  Course-specific information  AP Computer Science Intermediate Computer Science  Contact information I read email regularly. Email amauer-oats@cps.edu. I am willing to call or text with you. Make sure your student put your phone number on the parent page of the student information form &amp;hellip; or email me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus: AP CS</title>
      <link>http://wy-cs.info/resources/apcs-syllabus--2017-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 15:49:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wy-cs.info/resources/apcs-syllabus--2017-2018/</guid>
      <description>This document gives information specific to the AP Computer Science course. See the all course syllabus information as well.
AP Review We will do approximately three weeks of AP review before the AP exam. Second semester grades will be significantly impacted by AP test preparation.
Many people benefit from outside preparation. Start in February. As a rough guide, the Barron&amp;rsquo;s AP Computer Science A text is too easy and the Be Prepared for the AP Computer Science Exam in Java book by Litvin and Litvin is too difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus: Intermediate</title>
      <link>http://wy-cs.info/resources/intermediatecs-syllabus--2017-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 15:49:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wy-cs.info/resources/intermediatecs-syllabus--2017-2018/</guid>
      <description>This document details the information specific to Intermediate Computer Science. See the all course syllabus information as well.
Materials  Notebook - a lightweight paper notebook dedicated to computer science. USB Drive of any size. Picturing Programs book electronic version - downloaded onto flash drive. DrRacket programming environment - installed at home. WeScheme - Online only replacement for DrRacket. Use if you cannot install software. You have to read special instructions to make it work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grade Weights</title>
      <link>http://wy-cs.info/resources/grading-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 11:00:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wy-cs.info/resources/grading-scale/</guid>
      <description>The most common question people have is how grades are computed.
Grading weights and scale    Percent Category     20 Final Exam/Project (Quarterly)   40 Tests and Quizzes (individual)   20 Projects   20 Participation    We use the standard Whitney Young grading scale (90+ A, 80+ B, 70+ C, 60+ D, below 60 F).
Class participation will be four points per day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Integrity</title>
      <link>http://wy-cs.info/resources/academic-integrity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 16:51:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wy-cs.info/resources/academic-integrity/</guid>
      <description>Being honest and honorable regarding one’s academic integrity is essential in all of your classes.
Students are expected to adhere to the following honor code regarding all of their work in this class.
 “I have neither given nor received improper aid on this test/project.”   “Improper aid” includes, but is not limited to:
 copying another student’s work allowing another student to copy your work sharing the problems given on a test to a student who has not taken the test copying work from any online or electronic resource without citation chatting or texting with another student during a test in which computer use is allowed  On a project (not test), it is acceptable to give suggestions to a student who knows less than you do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Racket?</title>
      <link>http://wy-cs.info/resources/why-racket/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 20:12:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wy-cs.info/resources/why-racket/</guid>
      <description>Many people we encounter tell us they wish they knew how to code and then ask which programming language they should learn. Given the press that some programming languages get, this question is not surprising. But it is also wholly inappropriate. Learning to program in a currently fashionable programming language often sets up students for eventual failure. Fashion in this world is extremely short lived. A typical “quick programming in X” book or course fails to teach principles that transfer to the next fashion language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WeScheme</title>
      <link>http://wy-cs.info/resources/ics-wescheme-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 07:00:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wy-cs.info/resources/ics-wescheme-note/</guid>
      <description>Special notes for WeScheme users You can use WeScheme if you cannot install DrRacket. For example, if you have a Chromebook for your home computer.
There are a few differences:
 Omit the (require picturing-programs) line.
 (Chapter 3) Instead of copy and pasting in a picture, you need to copy the link for the image and use bitmap/url like this:
(bitmap/url&amp;#34;https://www.what-dog.net/Images/faces2/main004.jpg&amp;#34;)  (Chapter 6) Inside big-bang you need to use the phrase to-draw instead of on-draw that we use in DrRacket.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>